I made my first dollar writing online in
2014. I wrote a viral answer on a
littleknown website at the time called
Kora about my bodybuilding
transformation and how I had gone from
weighing less than 100 lb as a senior in
high school to putting on over 70 lbs of
muscle and becoming a shredded
bodybuilder by age 24. And at the top of
the short story I wrote, I put a before
and after image showing the
transformation. That Kora answer ended
up on the front page of Reddit and
accumulated over a million views in just
a few days. And I got probably a hundred
emails from guys who said, "I look just
like you did and I want to put on muscle
too." Which is how I came up with the
idea for my very first digital product,
an ebook called Skinny to Shredded. And
I made two of them, Skinny to Shredded
Workout Routines and Skinny to Shredded
Nutrition Guide. I spent the entire
weekend putting them together. I bought
www.nicholas Nicholas Cole.com, which is
the same domain I use as my primary
website today. I built a simple one-page
website using Squarespace. I wrote both
ebooks in Microsoft Word. I used some
pictures I'd taken with my bodybuilding
friends at the gym and some I'd taken
from trying to become a fitness model.
All these things I was trying to do at
the time. And I asked a designer at the
advertising agency I was working at if
she would help me create the covers. And
I bought her lunch as a thank you. Then
Sunday night, just 2 days later, I
turned my website live, made my ebooks
available for sale, and added a link to
the products at the bottom of that viral
Kora answer. It's still there on Quora
if you want to take a look. And I will
never forget sitting in our Monday
morning all hands meeting. My phone in
my pocket was just buzzing nonstop.
Stripe notification after stripe
notification after stripe notification.
And by lunch, I had earned more money
selling ebooks than I would make working
my full-time job all week. That simple
ebook series is how I made my first
dollar on the internet and my first $100
and my first $1,000 and my first $5,000
for months thereafter. It just kept
selling. Not a ton, but enough to put an
extra couple hundred bucks in my pocket
each month, which was a lot for me back
then. But more importantly, it
introduced me to this idea of leverage
on the internet. You can create
something once but continue to sell it
forever. Even a decade later, whenever I
tell this story, people still ask me
where they can buy those old ebooks.
That moment of making my first dollar
online changed my life and introduced me
to a completely different way of
thinking about what it means to provide
for yourself in the digital age. The old
path of go to college, get a job, work
for 40 years, then retire isn't the only
path anymore. If anything, that path is
dying. It's no longer viable and it's
being replaced by a new path that is
much more flexible, more lucrative, and
most of all, a lot more fun. And
remember, I was doing all of this back
in 2014 before all the incredible tools
and platforms we have today. So, if I
was starting over, here's the full road
map I would follow to make my first
dollar online and hopefully a lot more
than just a dollar. And for context,
since I launched that first digital
product way back in 2014, I have gone on
to generate over $30 million across
eight different business models building
digital products and providing services
online. I've generated over a million
self-publishing non-fiction books. I've
generated over a million with paid
newsletters. I've generated over a
million dollars with SAS. I've generated
over $3 million with consulting. I've
generated over $3 million with low
ticket digital products. I've generated
over $5 million with cohort-based
courses. I've generated over $5 million
with ghost writing services and I have
generated over $10 million with high
ticket group coaching programs. I only
share that so that you know where my
advice is coming from and also show you
there are lots of different ways to
monetize your knowledge online. So,
first let's walk through the road map at
a high level and then go through each
step so that by the end of this you know
exactly what to do, why you should do it
and how to make your first dollar online
and hopefully a lot more money
thereafter. The road map to your first
dollar online. There are seven steps to
making money online. None of them are
hard and the road map from where you are
today to where you want to go is very
straightforward. The hard part is
staying committed long enough to see
your sacrifices turn into Stripe
notifications. The road map goes like
this. Step one, pick a niche. The most
effective way to make money on the
internet is to become known for a niche
you own. And the smaller, more specific
the niche, the more likely you are to
become what I like to call niche famous.
You want people to associate you with
that niche because the more people
associate you with a specific niche, the
more products and services you can
launch within that niche over a
prolonged period of time. One of my
favorite examples is Ryan Holiday.
What's his niche? It's stoicism. He
writes articles about stoicism. He has a
newsletter about stoicism. He has a
podcast about stoicism. He's written 10
books about stoicism. And guess what?
When he goes to his publisher and says,
"I'm ready to write another book." And
they hand him another seven figure
advance, what do you think the topic of
the book is going to be? The book is
going to be about stoicism. This is the
whole game. You don't want to become
known broadly. You want to become known
for a niche you own. And I'm going to
walk you through my framework for
identifying the perfect most lucrative
niche for you. Step two, start writing
online. So, the way you validate demand
for any product or service you want to
monetize inside of a niche is to start
writing about it. Is to start writing
online. And by the way, if you don't
know what niche or topic you want to
commit to, then the answer is to write
about anything and everything that is
interesting to you and see what sticks,
what's resonating with readers. What do
they want more of from you? What
questions do they have? I usually tell
people it takes at least 30 days of
writing and publishing every single day
to gather enough data to get a sense of
which direction you should move next,
which is the whole reason why we started
ship 30 for30. It's a 30-day writing
challenge that holds you accountable and
forces you to write and hit publish
every day for 30 days because that's
what you have to do. By the end of the
month, you have 30 pieces of published
content. That's the foundation of your
library. And more importantly, you have
30 data points. Those data points will
tell you where there's customer demand.
Step three, start a newsletter. So, to
sell any product or service, you need
emails. To build an email list, you need
to write online. and to effectively
write online and build a niche audience.
You need to commit to a niche. See how
each of these steps connect to each
other. So, think of your email list as
the engine of your entire business. The
more people you have on your email list,
the more money you will make. And I'll
walk you through my strategy for turning
social content into weekly newsletters.
But the big idea here is that your
newsletter should really just be the
longer form version of the same topics
you're writing about online. Step four,
create an offer. Once you've committed
to a niche, started writing online about
that niche, and started a weekly
newsletter in that niche, well, now it's
time to make your free readers a paid
offer. An offer is just how you solve
someone else's problem. And how you
solve someone else's problem is what
dictates your business model. So, for
example, if you solve someone else's
problem with information, maybe your
business model is selling ebooks like I
did, or starting a paid newsletter, or
launching a course. If you solve someone
else's problem with customtailored
advice, maybe your business model is
selling consulting. And if you solve
someone else's problem by doing the work
for them, maybe your business model is
selling services. You get the idea. And
I'll help you decide which offer and
business model is right for you based on
your chosen niche, skills, and goals.
Step five, make your first dollar. So,
if you have a product for sale in a
niche that helps someone solve an urgent
and painful and ideally expensive
problem in their life and in their
business and you write about that topic
on a social platform every single day
for 90 days in a row, you will probably
make your first dollar online. You might
even make your first $1,000 or $10,000
online. I have no idea. I don't have
control over the decisions you make or
how consistent you are. What I do know
is that it is very, very, very hard to
not make money online if you have a
helpful product for sale in a niche and
then you consistently create helpful
content in that niche for a prolonged
period of time. None of these things are
hard. The hard part is not giving up
before it happens. And by the way,
putting a product up for sale or
starting to sell a service is very
simple. I'll walk you through it. Step
six, gather testimonials. So, the
biggest mistake that I made with my
first digital product is that I put it
up for sale. I made some money and then
I never improved the product and I never
collected customer testimonials to use
in future marketing. In hindsight, I bet
I could have made my first $100,000
online if I had just done those two
simple things. Make the product better
and use customer testimonials to sell
more products, which is exactly what you
should do. And I will give you a
checklist you can use once your product
is live and selling to generate even
more revenue. And step seven, monetize
in more ways. So, the last step once
you've made your first dollar online is
to start stacking different business
models on top of each other so you can
generate more revenue per customer. For
example, if you have a paid newsletter,
why can't you downell subscribers on
specific ebooks? Or if you sell
services, why can't you upsell your best
clients on even more expensive
consulting? If you sell courses, why
can't you cross-ell other courses and
digital products? I have generated
millions of dollars selling individual
products and services, but I have
generated tens of millions of dollars
selling other things to existing
customers. This is the whole secret to
making money online and why the hardest
part of the journey is starting. Because
once you start becoming known for a
niche you own, you start writing online,
you start shipping your weekly
newsletter, and you start making money,
momentum begins working in your favor.
So that's the road map. Is it simple?
Yes. But is it easy? Absolutely not. How
to make money online is literally one of
the most popular topics on the internet.
Everyone wants to do it. But the reason
not everyone is successful is because
they think there's some secret key on
the keyboard that when you press it
gives you passive revenue with no work
required. And that's just not true.
Making money online in any niche selling
any type of product or service takes
work. But once you build the skills and
you master the fundamentals of writing
online and learn how to monetize in
multiple different ways, you can make
money forever. So, I want to set you up
for success. Let's walk through each
step so you know exactly what to do, why
it's important, and how to do it
correctly. Step one, pick a niche. Your
niche should be an industry where you
have what I like to call an information
advantage. So, an information advantage
just means that you know more things
about this industry than the average
person. For example, if you've worked as
a nurse in a hospital, you have an
information advantage in healthcare. If
you played hockey as a kid, you have an
information advantage in athletics. If
you're obsessed with Pokémon cards, you
have an information advantage in
collectibles. The easiest way to
identify where you have an information
advantage is to audit these three areas
of time spent. So, first, jobs. Any job
you've ever had has given you an inside
look at that particular industry, which
means you know things, even if they're
simple, fairly basic things, that the
average person does not because they've
never worked a job in that industry
before. For example, if you've worked in
retail, you inherently know more about
working in retail than someone who has
never worked in retail before. This also
applies to people close to you who hold
jobs of their own. For example, my dad
is a spine surgeon. Just by being his
son, I have soaked up lots of random
knowledge and terminology when it comes
to spine surgeries. So, in a small way,
this gives me an information advantage.
Second are hobbies. So, anything you've
ever gotten interested in, either as a
kid or an adult, means you have spent a
prolonged period of time learning about
it, which means you have an information
advantage and you know things the
average person doesn't. For example, if
you spent your college years teaching
yourself music production, then you know
more about music production than someone
who has never taught themselves that
skill before. This also applies to
people close to you who expose you to
hobbies and interests of their own. For
example, if your best friend is a pilot
and flies planes, you probably don't
even realize how much you've learned
just by being their friend and listening
to them talk about that interest. In a
small way, this gives you an information
advantage. And third, experiences. So,
anything you have personally experienced
means you have an information advantage
in that particular experience. And the
more rare or unique the experience, the
more rare and unique the information
advantage. For example, if you've
experienced a parent overcoming a
sickness, that's an information
advantage. Or if you've experienced
traveling to a certain country or done
something crazy like jumped out of an
airplane, those are information
advantages. You know more about those
things than people who have never done
those things before. For example, back
in 2016, I was a columnist for Inc.
Magazine. I wrote a daily column about
creativity and business. So when I
started ghost writing and providing
writing services to founders and
business owners a year later in 2017 and
they would ask me to help them get their
own writing in major publications, I
could tell them because I was already
doing that for myself. I had an
information advantage. You should not
choose a niche or pick a topic without
some sort of information advantage. This
is probably the biggest mistake people
make when they decide to start writing
and creating content online with the
hopes of one day making money. They
think their niche can be anything and it
can't. No one is going to listen to you
talk about a topic you know nothing
about. The only reason people follow
people online is because there is an
information advantage trade happening.
You know things about this topic most
other people don't. People follow you to
learn those things in a fraction of the
time. So they don't have to go through
all the work you had to go through in
order to learn the things that you now
know. That's it. And if that doesn't
convince you to start with a niche where
you already have an existing information
advantage, here's an even more logical
way of thinking about it. When it comes
to making money on the internet, there
are lots of marketing and monetization
skills you need to learn, right? You
need to learn how to write clearly. You
need to learn how to generate infinite
ideas within a niche. You need to learn
how to hook people's attention. You need
to learn how to retain people's
attention. You need to learn how to move
readers from social platforms over to
your email list. You need to learn how
to write compelling emails, compelling
enough to keep them subscribed and
ultimately buy something of greater
value. You need to learn how to build a
landing page. You need to learn how to
write a landing page. You need to learn
how to process payments on a landing
page. You need to learn about upsells
and downells to increase each customer's
lifetime value. The list goes on and on.
And none of these skills are hard to
learn. Each one maybe takes 5 or 10
hours to reach a moderate level of
proficiency. That's nothing. That's like
a Saturday morning. That's a weekend.
But now imagine trying to learn all of
these new skills while simultaneously
applying them to a niche you know
absolutely nothing about. You have no
information advantage. Well, if you
thought building all those marketing and
monetization skills was a lot of work,
congratulations because the work just
doubled. Now you have to learn all of
those things and start from the very
beginning learning about an industry
you've never worked in, never had a
hobby in, and never experienced. but you
picked it because it seemed popular or
lucrative and you thought that was the
shortcut to success. So, here's a little
secret for you. The shortcut is always
the longer road in disguise and you
would get to where you're trying to go a
whole lot faster if you just started
with something you already knew a lot
about. Now, again, an information
advantage does not mean you have won
some huge award or made millions of
dollars. An information advantage quite
literally just means you know more than
someone who hasn't done that thing
before. A silly example I like to use
with students inside our AI writing
school is imagine you love reading. You
love reading thrillers and you want to
start writing online about the best
thrillers to read. You want to start a
thrillers book club. So what's your
information advantage? Well, it might be
something as simple as over the past 10
years I have read over 500 thrillers.
That's all it has to be. Your
information advantage is just context.
It helps the reader understand why they
should listen to you. And you might not
realize it, but you look for this signal
every single day when you scroll on your
preferred social platform. So the next
time you're scrolling X or LinkedIn or
Tik Tok or Instagram reels or YouTube,
just pay attention to what grabs your
attention. It's almost always a piece of
content that does three things. First,
it speaks directly to a niche interest
of yours. Second, it promises to help
you either solve a problem or help you
achieve an outcome. And third, it starts
with some form of context, meaning the
writer or creator tells you their
information advantage. Usually, it's
something like, "I've been an interior
designer for 10 years, so if you want to
remodel your kitchen, let me give you a
few tips to make it look professional
without blowing through your budget."
This simple hook is doing all three of
those things. First, it's speaking
directly to a niche interest, interior
design. Second, it's promising to help
achieve a desired outcome, remodel your
kitchen without blowing through your
budget. And third, it begins with the
creator sharing their information
advantage, which is really just context
for why you can trust them. They've been
an interior designer for 10 years. So
when you niche down, all you're really
doing is committing to write and create
lots and lots of content about a
specific topic in an industry where you
have some sort of information advantage.
Now, whenever I explain this idea of
niching down in an industry where you
have an information advantage, I always
get asked the same three questions. And
the thing is, they're not even really
questions. There are more objections to
this strategy phrased as questions. So,
not only do I want to answer them for
you, but I want to help you understand
why these objections are incorrect and
just clever ways you've convinced
yourself to avoid taking action.
Question number one, but Cole, if I pick
a niche, won't that exclude certain
people? Won't that mean I'll be limiting
my opportunity? I won't make any money.
This is by far the biggest question and
objection people have when it comes to
niching down. First of all, people think
that when they pick a niche, that means
they can't speak to everyone. And that's
correct. You can't speak to everyone
because when you try to speak to
everyone, you end up speaking to no one.
For example, just think about who you
follow on social media. Do you follow
one person for everything? No, of course
not. You follow one person for fitness
advice and you follow another person for
travel recommendations and you follow
another person for investment strategies
and you follow another person for news
and trending topics and you follow
another person for memes and pop
culture. It would be impossible for you
to speak on all topics for all people.
Second, it's not until you commit to a
niche for a prolonged period of time
that you realize just how deep each
niche can go. So, for example, I've been
writing about digital writing and
writing on the internet since 2015.
That's over a decade. And today, after
writing thousands and thousands of
articles and newsletters and tweets and
making YouTube videos and writing books
and recording podcasts all on the same
topic, I am still coming up with new
ways of explaining concepts to readers.
So, the deeper you go in a niche, the
more you realize how much more there is
to say. But if you haven't done this
work yet, then yes, it's very easy to
think that you can write about 10
different niches and be the best person
to listen to in each of them. We call
this blissful ignorance. Question number
two, but Cole, what if I have lots of
interests and lots of information
advantages? Which one should I pick? I
get it. I have lots of interests and
information advantages, too. When I was
17 years old, I was one of the highest
ranked World of Warcraft players in
North America. I have an information
advantage in online gaming. When I was
in college, I completely changed my
physique and became a bodybuilder. I
have an information advantage in fitness
and bodybuilding. When I graduated from
college, my first job was working as a
copywriter at an advertising agency. I
have an information advantage in
advertising and marketing and how ad
agencies work. When I quit my job in
2016 to work for myself, I started and
scaled a ghostwriting agency to millions
of dollars in revenue. I have an
information advantage in ghostwriting. I
mean, the list goes on and on. I've
built multiple 7-figure companies, but I
also love wine and luxury sports cars.
I'm a tequila snob. My siblings and I
all grew up playing piano and violin,
and I played classical piano for 20
years. All of these are potential right
answers. So, here's the exercise I coach
writers through inside our writing
programs to help them identify the best
information advantage for them. First,
what you should do is list out every
job, hobby, and meaningful experience
you've ever had. What you will find is
you have a lot of different information
advantages to choose from. Most of which
you probably take for granted. Next,
looking at that list of say 10 or 20
information advantages, stackrank them
by knowledge. So out of that entire
list, which one do you know the most
about which topic second, which topic
third? You should end up with a list
that is organized from most
knowledgeable to least knowledgeable. So
for example, one of my best friends is a
therapist and I have been in therapy for
over a decade. I'm a huge proponent of
it. So yes, I do have an information
advantage in this area, but I would
hardly consider myself qualified on the
topic. So that would probably be near
the bottom of my list. Lastly, take the
top three to five information advantages
you are most knowledgeable about from
your list and start writing about those
topics online. You don't have to commit
to a niche yet, but at least this gives
you some direction. These are the topics
where you possess the most working
knowledge. So write about them. And then
out of those three to five topics, see
which one or two perform the best. And
the way you should measure performance
is first, which of these topics do
readers find most interesting? You can
identify this even in small ways by
looking at views, likes, and comments
relative to all your other posts. So for
example, if you write 10 tweets and nine
of them all get 100red views, but one of
them gets 300 views, that is a 3x
difference. That is a data point. A lot
of times people discount these early
signals because they think what they're
looking for is a post with a million
views. That's not true. There might be
more zeros, but the logic is still the
same. Write lots of things, look for
tiny outliers, and double down on those.
And just repeat for a decade. And
second, which of these topics do you
find most interesting? As you write
about these three to five different
topics where you have a strong
information advantage, I promise you
will very quickly start to realize which
ones you enjoy writing about the most
and which ones you thought you would
enjoy writing about but actually find
boring. This is an important part of the
learning process. The final answer to
what your niche should be is then the
result of this exercise, checking these
three boxes. So, it's a topic where you
already possess a strong information
advantage. It's a topic you see
performing well with readers in the form
of engagement, even if it's small. And
it's a topic you enjoy writing about,
and the more you write about it, the
more you realize you have to say.
Whatever topic checks those three boxes
should be your niche. And if you want to
make money online, then you should
commit to that niche for a prolonged
period of time because none of the
outcomes you desire happen overnight.
Question number three. But Cole, I
understand all of that, but I want the
shortcut. I just want money to rain down
from the sky. Can you just tell me what
the most lucrative niche is so I can go
do that? Here is the honest answer. The
most lucrative niche for me is going to
be different than the most lucrative
niche for you. That's because how
lucrative a niches has very little to do
with the niche itself and much more to
do with the writer or creator who
commits to it. For example, I could tell
you that the most lucrative niche in the
world right now is advice for millennial
women dealing with postpartum
depression. If you write about that
topic and launch digital products in
that niche, you can crush and probably
make loads of money. Why? Because that
demographic is chronically online. They
love to shop. They have high purchasing
power. They tend to control a lot of the
purchasing decisions for the household.
And they have an urgent and painful
problem. They desperately want help
solving. Okay, great. There's your
answer. The problem is you aren't going
to go pursue that niche. Why? First,
because you probably don't have an
information advantage in that niche. So
now you see the problem. You can't help
people solve a problem you've never
experienced and know nothing about. And
second, because you probably aren't
interested in that topic. So even if you
know it has the potential to be
lucrative, you aren't going to stay
consistent and disciplined and
interested long enough to successfully
monetize it. Which is why I tell writers
over and over and over again. The best
niche is the one you don't give up on.
Whatever topic you know you will still
be interested in 10 years later is the
right answer. Because I promise it
doesn't matter how lucrative you think
another niche is. If you don't have an
information advantage in it and you
aren't genuinely interested in
continuing to learn about it, you aren't
going to succeed. You're going to get
really excited about it for 2 days and
then give up. You're going to get bored
and when things get hard or monotonous,
you aren't going to push through. And
then you're going to avoid taking
accountability for your lack of
commitment and blame the niche instead,
hoping that if you pick a different
niche, an even more seemingly lucrative
niche, the problem will magically
disappear and then money will rain down
from the sky. This is the vicious cycle
people stay in for years, sometimes
decades. I promise the problem is never
the niche. The problem is you keep
trying to find the shortcut instead of
just committing to a topic you know a
lot about and want to help other people
become knowledgeable about too. Step
two, start writing online. Once you've
identified your niche, the easiest way
to validate demand for any future
product or service is to start writing
about it. Is to start writing online.
And there are five formats you need to
learn how to write if you want to build
a niche audience. Format number one,
short form. So, these are bite-sized
pieces of textbased content like tweets.
But these can also double as scripts or
talking points for short form videos,
Tik Toks, Instagram reels, YouTube
shorts, even long form YouTube videos.
Format number two, atomic essays. These
are 300word essays, short enough to be
written in 30 minutes or less, but long
enough that you can start to practice
all the fundamental skills of writing
online like headlines, formatting,
writing rhythms, etc. This is a format
that we invented for our beginner
writing program, Ship 30 for30, and it
has since become an internet phenomenon.
Even people who have never taken ship 30
for30 before write atomic essays using
our software, TypeShare. Format number
three, LinkedIn carousels. So, these are
listicles turned into multimedia
slideshows that are the highest
performing format on LinkedIn. These
carousels can also double as carousels
on Instagram or other image-based social
platforms like Pinterest. Format number
four, X articles. These are 800 plusword
blog posts published as articles on X,
but can also be republished across your
website, Medium, even your weekly
newsletter. Long- form articles can also
be the foundation of your entire content
strategy. And you can extract dozens of
short form posts from each one. And
format number five, AI prompts. So
lastly, you can get leverage on your
writing skills by turning your favorite
AI platform into your own personal
writing assistant and then turning those
prompts into more content or assets for
your niche. So, for example, since my
niche is digital writing, I often share
writing or editing or brainstorming and
outlining prompts with my audience. And
I train writers and creators on how to
write all five of these formats inside
our AI writing school. So, if you're
brand new to writing online, this is an
easy place to start because each format
has different rules and each platform
has different nuances. I like to think
of each format and social platform as a
different sublanguage of digital writing
or writing in the digital age. Now, I
know what you're probably thinking. But
Cole, which platform is the best? How do
I go viral? What time of day should I
post? To which I kindly say, you are
asking the wrong questions. Everyone
loves to get fixated on all these little
incremental decisions that in the long
run really don't matter. My personal
point of view, and the point of view
I've been preaching for over a decade,
is there is no one perfect platform, and
the performance of any individual post
is not what's important. I have gone
viral more times than I can count across
a wide variety of different platforms.
I've generated over a billion views on
my writing. And I'm telling you, going
viral is not what solves your problems
or allows you to build a business and
make money online. My entire thesis for
writing in the digital age is that it's
all about the library. So, let me walk
you through this. The bigger your
library of content in a niche. The wider
your footprint, the more likely you are
to become niche famous. The more you
establish yourself as a leading voice in
a particular niche, the more people who
become interested in that niche become
interested in listening to you. The more
people who follow you, the more your
email list grows, the more potential
customers you will attract. The more
customers you attract in a niche, the
more you can sell those customers, not
once, but many times over many years.
And the more successfully you monetize a
niche, the more excess cash you will be
able to reinvest in yourself and your
own content and continuing to expand
your footprint in your niche until
eventually you and the niche become
synonymous and you have successfully
become known for a niche you own. On top
of that, your library of content is
yours. You own it, which means you can
do whatever you want with it. When a new
social platform comes out, you can copy
paste all your highest performing posts
over to that new platform and powerle
level your niche dominance there, too.
You can turn tweets into Tik Toks, Tik
Toks into Instagram reels, reels into
YouTube shorts, and a bunch of shorts
all on the same topic into a YouTube
long- form video. You can turn articles
into newsletters. You can turn
newsletters into articles. You could
smash 10 articles or newsletters on the
same topic together and self-publish it
as a book on Amazon. You could turn your
book on Amazon into a lead magnet to
capture more emails. You could expand
your book into an online course. You
could expand your course into a coaching
program. The list goes on and on. In
fact, if you want an example, this is
what I did with my last book, Writer
Career Paths. I wrote this entire book
online. I wrote each chapter as a
newsletter first, and then when it was
done, I smashed all those newsletters
together, did a little light editing,
and self-published it on Amazon. And now
that book generates an extra th,000
bucks a month. The point is, the most
valuable asset you could possibly build
for yourself is a library of content in
a niche over a prolonged period of time
because you can reuse all of that
content and double and triple and
quadruple monetize all of that content
for decades into the future. The library
matters more than virality. Step three,
start a newsletter. I have been writing
online since 2007 and over the past 20
years, digital distribution and social
platforms have changed a lot. The
biggest change being from follower-based
content to interestbased content. So,
for example, back in the early 2010s, if
you had 10,000 followers and you made a
post, that post got shown to a
meaningful chunk of your followers. That
was the whole point of building an
audience on social platforms. More
followers meant more distribution. But
then around 2016, social platforms
started to change. Your newsfeed stopped
being about who you followed and started
being more about topics of interest.
Showing you posts from people you didn't
follow, but who created content within a
niche the algorithm knew you cared
about. All of a sudden, followers didn't
matter. What mattered was how well your
content performed when the algorithm
presented it to groups of people
interested in that topic. If people
engaged, platforms would distribute your
content to wider and wider audiences,
causing you to go viral. And if your
content didn't perform, then your
distribution would fall off a cliff,
regardless of whether you had a,000
followers or a million followers. Today,
followers are an almost meaningless
metric. I have helped over 15,000 people
start writing online, and beginners love
to think that more followers will
somehow solve all their problems. A
couple things here. First of all,
everyone starts at zero. When I started
writing on Kora back in 2014, right out
of college, I didn't create a new
account and win the lottery and get a
5,000 follower head start. Every single
person who has ever built an audience
online started at zero. Second,
followers are a lagging indicator. You
write valuable content in a niche and
then people follow you. People don't
follow you and then you start writing
valuable content. So, you have to build
the skill before people will give you
their attention. And third, social
platforms are no longer follower-based.
They are interest based, which means
having more followers doesn't actually
give you an advantage. You could have
hundreds of thousands of followers and
still write content that only gets a,000
views. I know because I have over a
quarter million followers on X and the
majority of my posts reach less than 1%
of that audience. Conversely, you could
start a brand new account, have zero
followers, and go nuclear viral on your
first post if the content is good
enough. I just watched this happen. I
went on this brand new podcast on
YouTube and the guy's very first
interview on a brand new channel with
zero subscribers got half a million
views in its first week. Which means the
whole point of writing and creating
content on social platforms is not
really to build an audience on rented
digital land. The point is to do two
things. First, just focus on building a
library of helpful content in a niche
over a prolonged period of time. And
second, use the distribution social
platforms provide to bring your rented
audience over to an owned platform like
email. So, how do you do that? By
starting a weekly newsletter and then
reminding readers on social platforms,
hey, by the way, I also write about this
same topic even more in depth over here.
Your newsletter is just the expanded
version of your social content. It's
just more. So, in ship 30 for30, we call
this lean writing. Lean writing is the
strategy of expanding short form content
into long- form content and compressing
long- form content into lots and lots of
short form content. This is how you go
from a viral tweet to an atomic essay to
a LinkedIn carousel to an ex article to
an ebook to a paid digital product to an
online course to an entire business.
Every single idea or topic you write
about in a niche can be expanded or
compressed into a wide variety of
different content formats. For example,
I recently wrote this long- form
newsletter on six revenue streams to
become a six-figure fiction writer. It
was 3,500 words, lots of examples, lots
of images. Took me almost 10 hours to
write start to finish. But I could also
compress this entire 3500word newsletter
into 280 characters by just writing a
tweet that lists out the six revenue
streams to earn six figures as a fiction
writer. books, beta reader community,
paid newsletter, digital products,
affiliate commissions, and paid
workshops. So, why would someone read a
3500word newsletter on the exact same
topic if they could just read the 280
character tweet that gives them all the
answers, one word, more. The only
difference between short form and long-
form content is more. More tips, more
stories, more lessons, more reasons,
more mistakes, more examples, more
explanation, more images, more, more,
more. Your newsletter does not and
should not be about a completely
different topic. It should be about the
same topic in your chosen niche, just
more. Step four, create an offer.
Writing and creating content on social
platforms is how you get access to
unlimited distribution. So, each social
platform has hundreds of millions, if
not billions of users. So, I promise no
matter what niche you pick, your target
readers are there. You just have to stay
consistent long enough for them to find
you. and for your content to appear in
their feed. Your newsletter is how you
retain your most engaged readers and
build a list of potential customers.
Anyone who voluntarily moves from a
distracting, fleeting social platform
over to your email list is essentially
raising their hand saying, "I am
interested in this topic. I find the
content you are creating helpful and I
might even be willing to give you money
if you help me solve an even more
urgent, even more painful, even more
expensive, even more valuable problem in
my life and/or my business. Which means
your offer is really just how you solve
someone else's problem or help them
unlock a desirable outcome. And there is
no right answer. In fact, there might
even be multiple right answers. You
could help someone by selling them more
advanced information. You could help
someone by coaching them one- on-one.
You could help someone by doing the work
for them. Eventually, as you build each
of these different marketing and
monetization skills, you may end up
helping them in all of these different
ways. That that's ultimately the goal.
But the magic word here is congruence.
Where beginners tend to mess up is they
think that their social content needs to
be different from their newsletter
content, which needs to be different
from their offer. No, that is not true.
Your social content is the short form
version of your newsletter content. Your
newsletter content is the longer form
version of your social content. And your
offer is the even longer, even more
valuable version of both your social
content and your newsletter content. So
for example, I write about digital
writing, how to write on the internet,
and all the different ways you can
monetize writing in the digital age. I
write about these topics on social
platforms like X and LinkedIn and
Substack. And I create videos on these
topics on YouTube and Instagram etc. But
I also write about these same topics in
more depth and more detail in my art and
biz of writing newsletter. And then I
also write about these same topics in
even more detail with more examples,
giving writers more templates and more
AI prompts with more access answering
more questions on live sessions and in
fiveday sprints or twoe boot camps or
30-day cohorts inside of our AI writing
school. So, think of it like a supply
chain. Your goal is you want to move
rented readers from social platforms
over to an owned platform like email all
the way to the end with some sort of
paid product or community or service.
And when it comes to supply chains,
simplicity is velocity. So the more
congruent each step is to the one before
it, the more likely people are to keep
moving from point A to point B to point
C. The less congruent each next step is
to the one before it, the less likely
people are to keep moving because they
don't know what to expect next. So, what
kind of offer should you create? Well,
there are nine different business models
that you can choose from, and they all
work. I know because over the past
decade, I have generated over a million
dollars in revenue inside of each of
these different business models. You
have software. We did this with our SAS
platforms, Typeshare and Ghostbase. With
AI, the average person can now vibe code
a lightweight piece of software and
charge a subscription fee for using it.
This is the hardest offer type for the
average person to execute, but it is
becoming easier and easier, and so it's
worth mentioning. Next, you have
self-publishing. So, I've written over
10 books on Amazon, including the
bestseller, The Art and Business of
Online Writing. You should think of your
newsletter as a vehicle for writing book
chapters on a weekly basis. And as your
pile of newsletters on a topic begins to
grow, eventually you'll be able to smash
them together and self-publish them as a
product. Then you have digital products.
So I've built nearly a dozen different
standalone digital products at this
point, including Category Newsletter
Creator, Low Ticket Launchpad, Substack
Starter Kit, Self-Publishing Studio. I
mean, the list goes on and on. A digital
product is usually a text and video
course on a specific topic helping your
target customer solve a specific problem
andor achieve a specific outcome. And
the average price point for these types
of digital products is usually between
$99 and about $350. Then you have agency
services. So from 2017 to 2021, I built
the first ghostwriting agency for
founders and executives scaling to
millions of dollars in revenue.
Providing a service or scaling it into
an agency just means instead of teaching
someone how to solve a problem or
achieve an outcome themselves, you are
getting paid to do the work for them.
Then you have paid newsletters. So for
example, our paid newsletter, write with
AI, is one of the biggest education
newsletters on Substack. It does over
$300,000 in annual recurring revenue and
over a million dollars in annual revenue
as a vertical within our portfolio of
writing businesses. Paid newsletters are
where you gate highly specific technical
or exclusive content behind a payw wall
and you're usually charging somewhere in
the ballpark of $9 to $49 per month
depending on the category of content.
Then you have paid communities. So we
run a large community called AI writing
school that does over half a million per
year in annual recurring revenue and
over a million dollars per year as a
vertical between sprints and boot camps
and cohorts and other experiences that
we run. A paid community is basically
like combining a paid newsletter and a
suite of digital products together and
usually costs between $9 and $99 per
month. Again, depending on the category
of content, you also have one-on-one
coaching and consulting. So, in 2023, I
built and then exited a company called
Category Pirates. That was another
six-figure paid newsletter on Substack
with a multisefigure consulting business
on the back of it. Coaching or
consulting is really just the high-end
version of a digital product. Instead of
selling people a text and video course
for them to go through on their own,
coaching usually just means repeating
all that same information to someone on
a one-on-one call or set of calls live.
You're just personalizing it to them.
You also have cohort-based experiences.
So, I am the co-founder of the largest
writing challenge on the internet called
Chip 30 for30 that has helped over
15,000 people start writing online and
generated millions of dollars in
revenue. A cohort-based course usually
combines a digital product style
curriculum with live sessions and
community elements that last for a
finite amount of time. So, in the case
of Ship 30 for30, students would
participate in the challenge for 30
days. And lastly, you have hybrid
one-on-one/group
coaching. So, this is the model that
we've run for our more advanced program,
Premium Ghost Writing Academy, which has
helped over 2,000 students enter the
lucrative world of ghostriting and has
generated over $10 million in total
revenue. Group coaching is typically in
the price range of $5,000 to $10,000 and
involves pairing students with coaches
to guide them through a constructed
curriculum along with live sessions,
community elements, ongoing education,
anything else you want to include. This
is by far the most complex offer type
because it involves so many different
fulfillment mechanisms. I share all of
this to help you understand that every
single business model and offer type can
work and has the potential to scale to
millions of dollars in revenue. Each one
just requires different skills and has
different pros and cons. So, let me give
you a quick crash course on how you
should make this decision for yourself.
The right offer for you is skills
multiplied by time horizon. So, a lot of
times people choose to pursue a business
model or offer type because it seems
lucrative or easy or they see someone
else succeeding with it and think, I
guess that's what I should do, too. But
the truth is, these are all bad ways of
making this decision. Every offer type
can be lucrative. Every offer type can
be scaled to millions and millions of
dollars in revenue. And I promise the
grass is always greener on the other
side of the fence. Every offer type
seems easy when someone else is doing
it. And every offer type seems hard and
annoying as soon as you choose to pursue
it. Which means the right way of making
this decision comes down to two things.
First, skills. What are you good at?
What do you want to get good at? What
type of business do you want to run? And
second is time horizon. How fast do you
want or need to make money? Do you need
to make money now in order to pay rent
at the end of the month, or would you
rather make less money now, but more
money in a more scalable way later? So,
let's walk through a few examples so you
understand how to make this decision.
Let's start with skills. If you really
enjoy working with people and want to
continue building skills where you
interact with students or customers
live, then you should probably pursue an
offer type that involves those elements.
So maybe cohort-based courses or paid
communities or one-on-one coaching and
consulting. Conversely, if you hate
interacting with people and just want to
write and create content, maybe you
shouldn't pursue a communityoriented
offer type and pick something more
asynchronous. Things like selling
digital products or having a paid
newsletter or self-publishing books on
Amazon or vibe coding software. There is
no one right answer, but it would be a
mistake to pick an offer type that
involves a handful of skills you don't
have, you don't enjoy, and you don't
want to do on a consistent basis, even
if that offer type appears to be more
lucrative or you see someone else
succeeding with it. And the reason is
because if it's not something you
inherently enjoy and care about and want
to get better at, you're going to give
up. You're going to get bored. You will
not have the intrinsic motivation to
push through moments of frustration. So
pick an offer that aligns with your
skills, not what you see someone else
succeeding with online. Second, time
horizon. So the second variable is your
time horizon. How long can you wait to
make money? For example, if you need
money now, you should start with a
service. Why? Because services will
always generate the most revenue the
fastest. Why do services generate the
most revenue the fastest, you ask?
Because you don't need a thousand
customers. You don't need a hundred
customers. You don't even need 10
customers. You need one client to pay
you $3,000 a month. And that is
significantly more achievable in a short
amount of time relative to all other
business models and offer types. The
problem with services, however, is while
they are quick to generate cash, they
are also quick to plateau. And they
require exponentially harder skill sets
in order to scale. It's very common for
people to go from zero to $10,000 per
month providing services. But it is much
less common to see people do what's
required to scale from $10,000 per month
to say $50,000 per month or $100,000 per
month and build a million-doll business.
Conversely though, offer types like paid
newsletters and paid communities and
software or anything recurring tends to
grow much slower in the beginning.
Again, why? Because the less you charge,
the more customers you need. You need
volume. And the way you typically
attract these customers is by creating
content online. And creating content
takes time. So, these business models
tend to be much slower to start, but the
trade-off is once they begin to work and
build momentum. They can scale
significantly easier than services or
one-on-one coaching and consulting, for
example. So, a lot of the decision of
which business model and offer type to
choose just comes down to what skills
you have and want to improve and the
time horizon over which you will measure
your success. And the answer to which
business model and offer type is right
for you entirely depends on where you're
at on the journey. For example, I've
reached a point where I don't need to
make money now. Grinding out an extra
$5,000 doesn't do anything for me
anymore. Which means all of my decisions
need to be in service of sacrificing
money now to build something more
scalable in the future. But 10 years
ago, when I was first starting out, that
was not the right answer for me at that
time. 10 years ago, I wanted money now.
I needed money now. And I was willing to
grind in order to make it happen because
$5,000 was a lot of money back then to
me. In fact, that was my entire net
worth. So, let me make this decision
really easy for you. If you are brand
new to making money online, even though
all of these business models and offer
types are available and potentially
lucrative, I would encourage you to
start with these two. Either digital
products, so a $99 to $350 text and
video course standalone, teaching people
how to solve some sort of problem or
achieve some sort of outcome in your
niche or services. a $3,000 to $5,000
per month recurring service where you do
the work for someone else, most likely a
business owner of some kind. These are
the two business models and offer types
most likely to generate money. Now, more
importantly, every other business model
is really just a more advanced version
of one of these two offer types. So, I
would recommend doing the beginner
versions first and then look to add
other more advanced and complex
monetization models to your business
thereafter. Step five, make your first
dollar. Here's a riddle for you. If you
do not have a product or service for
sale, how much money can you make? The
answer is zero. You can make $0. In
order to make your first dollar online,
you have to have something for sale. It
is impossible to generate revenue if you
do not have an offer. Which means if you
want to make money online, your first
measure for success is not to build the
perfect product or become a
world-renowned industry expert so that
you can one day launch the most
innovative service ever created. Your
first measure for success is to
literally just have something for sale.
Then, and only then, are you able to
generate any revenue at all.
Perfectionism is the enemy of progress.
So, inside our writing programs, I
preach this idea often of practicing in
public. Nothing will teach you more
about your own writing than doing it in
front of other people. And nothing will
teach you more about how to improve your
product or service than charging money
for it. So the faster that you put
yourself in that position, the faster
you will learn, the faster you will
improve your product or service, the
faster you will make money online.
Unfortunately, a lot of times people
postpone building products or providing
services because they're afraid of
disappointing customers. They're worried
their product won't be good enough or
their service won't help someone. But
the truth is, even if that were to
happen, disappointment is a positive
signal because now you know what to fix.
Now you know what to improve so that it
doesn't happen again. The first digital
product you create is going to be your
worst one. The first time you provide a
service is going to be the worst version
of that service. It is inevitable. But
you cannot get to the second version
until you provide that first version.
And often times we are much more
critical of ourselves than our customers
are of us. Like looking back, my first
digital product was horrible. There were
so many skills I didn't have yet and so
many things I would do very differently
today. But customers weren't nearly as
critical. In fact, many of them loved
it. The point is, you can't learn how to
write the perfect piece of content or
build the perfect digital product or
provide the perfect service by thinking
about it by yourself. You can only learn
how to improve something once it's in
front of someone else. Then improvement
becomes obvious. But Cole, shouldn't I
wait until my audience is bigger before
I launch my product or service? You can,
but my advice would be to have something
available for sale sooner rather than
later for a few reasons. First of all,
having a paid offer actually elevates
your perceived value. So, when you have
a digital product or say you provide a
service for a certain type of person,
people assume you are established
because established people have
businesses and established people make
money. So having something for sale
actually makes it easier to attract your
target readers and potential customers
and further positions you as a leader in
your chosen niche. Second, as your
audience grows, you might as well
monetize on the way up. Every writer or
creator I know wishes they had started
monetizing sooner. The reason is because
building an audience online takes a lot
of effort. So if you're going to
prioritize that much effort into
something, you might as well collect
revenue along the way. There's very
little to be gained by delaying
monetization. you don't necessarily make
more money later as the result of doing
that. And third, this thinking implies
customers only buy once, and that is not
true. The longer you write within a
niche and the more products or services
you provide within that niche, the more
repeat customers you will attract. So,
the sooner you monetize and have
something for sale, the sooner you will
begin to build your recurring or
reoccurring base of customers. Step six,
gather testimonials. The moment someone
hands you money, the improvement cycle
begins. Without question, this is the
biggest mistake I made with my fitness
ebooks way back in 2014. I ended up
selling thousands of copies of those
ebooks to customers all over the world
and didn't once ask for feedback or
launch updated versions or ask for
testimonials to use in future marketing.
If I had, I could have easily turned
that fitness ebook series into a
six-figure, maybe even a sevenf
figureure business. So, let's make sure
that you don't make that same mistake.
Once you have a product or service for
sale, here are the highest leveraged
things you can do to improve that
product or service and generate more
revenue. Improvement tip number one, you
should ask for feedback. If you sell a
digital product, you should email every
single person who buys and you should
ask them, "How did you find me in my
product?" This is going to tell you
which of your marketing efforts are
working and which of your social
platforms are bringing you customers.
And you should also ask them, "Was there
anything missing from the product that
would be helpful?" This will give you
insight into what could be improved. And
as an incentive, you can give every
single customer who gives you feedback
free access to any future upgrades you
make to the product. Now, the advanced
version of this would be to email every
single person who buys your product and
ask if they would be open to a 30inut
Zoom interview and you can give them
some sort of bonus or additional asset
in exchange. I cannot emphasize how
valuable these customer interviews are.
Customers will literally tell you the
answers. They will tell you what was
confusing. They will tell you what was
missing. They will tell you what they
would have paid more for. They will tell
you what other questions they still
have. They will tell you why they bought
your product in the first place.
Everyone loves to overcomplicate how to
build great digital products or provide
valuable services. But the truth is,
it's not complicated at all. It's just
tedious. Talk to every customer, record
the conversations, then go back through
each call recording and take their exact
words. how they phrased their biggest
problem or what they found confusing and
use those words to improve the product
and improve your marketing. If you want
to make more money, talk to more
customers. And if you sell a service,
you should ask these same questions to
every single one of your prospects and
your current clients. Questions like,
"How did you find me and my service?"
Again, this will tell you which of your
marketing efforts are working and which
of your social platforms are bringing
you qualified clients. You should ask
them, "What's the biggest problem in
your business right now?" This will tell
you what they care most about, which
should be what you anchor the value of
your service to. And this will also tell
you what other problems you should
potentially charge even more money to
help them solve, upselling the client on
additional services. And you should also
ask them, is there anything about my
process you find confusing or would like
me to change? The more you can ask
clients directly how they would prefer
to receive information or communicate or
work with you, the better you're going
to understand how to help them. You will
also be able to spot patterns between
clients and client types, making it
easier for you to anticipate these
preferences with clients in the future.
When you ask people how to improve or
what you could do differently to make
them happier, they will always tell you.
But a surefire way to make less money is
to not ask at all. Improvement tip
number two, you should launch updated
versions. So when customers or clients
give you feedback, that feedback usually
leads to two types of upgrades. The
first is feedback to improve the
existing offer. So, as a general rule of
thumb, until your product or service is
generating at least a million dollars
per year, the answer is to not jump
around and launch more products or more
services. The right next step is to keep
improving the product until it's good
enough to become a seven-figure
business. This is what I did with my
ghostwriting agency, which I scaled to
millions of dollars in revenue. And this
is also what I did with Ship 30 for30,
which crossed a million dollars in
revenue in its first year operating as a
cohort-based course. The second type of
feedback is to expand the offer into an
upsell. So sometimes customer interviews
reveal other problems that you can help
them solve either with information in
the form of digital products or
additional services. So in this case,
it's actually counterproductive to try
and solve more and more and more
problems within your original product or
service because trying to solve too many
different problems ends up making that
product or service more confusing, not
necessarily more valuable. So instead,
you're better off breaking out these
problems and monetizing them as separate
products or separate services, otherwise
known as upsells. This is why the
hardest part of writing and making money
online is the beginning. It's starting.
Because once you start writing, and
especially once you launch your first
product or service, you very quickly
realize how much more you have to write
about and how many more products or
services you could provide people to
monetize over and over and over again.
And improvement tip number three, you
should gather testimonials. So lastly,
while testimonials or case studies are
certainly not required in order to
launch your first digital product or
service, cuz remember, everyone starts
at zero, they are incredible assets to
have for all your future marketing. So
your goal for your first thousand
customers is to collect a,000
testimonials. You should ask every
single person who buys something from
you, would you mind sharing a
testimonial? How did this help you? What
problem did you have and were you able
to fix it? What outcome were you hoping
to achieve and were you able to achieve
it? Testimonials themselves are
valuable, but in all honesty, what is
even more valuable is what each
testimonial teaches you about your
target customer. Their words will become
your marketing copy. Their stories will
become your transformation thesis. Their
fears will give you ideas of helpful
content you can create and share to help
them. Nothing will make you more money
than talking to your customers. I
repeat, nothing will make you more money
than talking to your customers. And step
seven, monetize in more ways. Once
you've started writing on social
platforms and once you've started moving
rented readers over to your owned email
list, and once you've launched some sort
of product or service and hopefully made
your first dollar online, there's really
only one step left, and that's to do it
again and do it more and do it in more
ways. Volume wins. So the first big idea
I want to share here is that there are
only two ways to scale a business. You
either scale with traffic, so you offer
more people the same thing, or you scale
with upsells, where you offer more
things to the same people. Now, the goal
is obviously to do both. Traffic means
marketing. So once you have a product or
service for sale, how much money you
make is directly correlated to how much
marketing you do and how much better you
do it. So, as a beginner, more marketing
first just means doing more of it. Post
more times across more platforms and
then once you've maxed out more, do it
better. How can you make each post
perform two times better, five times
better, 10 times better? If you want
more insight into this more better new
framework that I love from Alex Ramoszi,
I recommend reading this piece I wrote
on 20 lessons selling $20 million of
online writing courses. But upsells
means helping people solve more
problems. So if you sell digital
products, that means creating other
different digital products that help
people solve other different problems.
And if you sell services, that means
offering other different services,
helping clients solve other different
problems in their business. This is how
you extend LTV, the lifetime value of
each customer. And then from here, you
can add other offer types to monetize in
more ways with the ultimate goal being
to become a full stack writer. So this
won't happen overnight. In fact, it
probably won't even happen in your first
year. But eventually where you want to
end up is with a business that services
different customers at different price
points with different offer types. So
take a look at our digital writing
business for example. Our most
entry-level offer is actually my book,
The Art and Business of Online Writing.
It's $9 for the ebook or $19 for the
print book and it covers all the
fundamental principles of writing in the
digital age. This is usually where most
people start. Next is our paid
newsletter on Substack, Write with AI.
It costs $20 per month and provides
readers with additional digital writing
education as well as exclusive AI
prompts. So, this services a diverse
range of customers and is still very
price accessible. Our next most
expensive offer is our paid community on
school, our AI writing school. It costs
$99 per month and includes a lot of the
same information we share in our paid
newsletter, right, with AI, but also
gives students more AI prompts, more
templates, more trainings and mini
courses, and more access to us. Members
of AI writing school can come ask
questions every Monday. They can
workshop their writing. They can jump in
the hot seat and get feedback on
anything they'd like. They also get free
access to our 5-day writing sprints and
50% off any twoeek boot camps that we
run. From there, we have
audiencespecific
standalone digital products that people
can buy individually depending on what
they're interested in, what problem they
want to solve, what outcome they're
looking to achieve, or sometimes they
get them included in our AI writing
school. So, these include category
newsletter creator, low ticket
launchpad, Substack starter kit,
self-publishing studio, decision
journaling, LinkedIn AI, Ghostriter GPT.
I mean, I've built dozens of these. And
then lastly, we have our cohort-based
writing program, Ship 30 for30. So, this
is a 30-day writing challenge and for
that month is significantly more
hands-on than any of our other offers,
which is also why it's more expensive.
So, you see how each of these offer
types serves a slightly different type
of customer at a different price point,
all focused on digital writing education
and writing with AI. And the more ways
you monetize and the more different
types of customers you can help, the
more you will extend the lifetime value
of each customer and the more you can
reinvest in the creation of new products
and new services. And this is how you
make money online in a niche forever.